Army Putera Parta

Jakarta, ID | P: +6281282762153 | armyputera@gmail.com| linkedin.com/in/army-putera-silalahi

PROFFESIONAL PROFILE

Currently upskilling in data science through a comprehensive professional training. Actively looking for new opportunities in data analysis and machine learning, eager to apply my background in Python and SQL to real-world challenges. Graduated with a Bachelor of Science in Forestry Engineering from Bandung Institute of Technology. With more than two year working experience in forest utilization business permit as Forest Planner and three months working experience as data analyst and quality control of World Research Institute Indonesia. Has an interest in data science, data analyst, project management, and business development. Able to work independently or as a team. Army had nurtured communication, teamwork, and problem-solving skills while having great adaptability and willingness to learn.

EXPERIENCE

Purwadhika Digital School - Jakarta, Indonesia

Juni 2024 – Present

Data Scientist Program

- Generate insights from various data types (tabular, textual, geospatial, point cloud, imagery) across diverse domains.
- Develop analytical techniques (descriptive and inferential statistic) and automated routines for tabular and spatial analysis to support effective management in the given field.
- Provide assistance and guidance to relevant stakeholders on best practices for data analysis and visualization.

PT. Sanimardani Resources (PT Sumalindo Lestari Jaya IV) – Jakarta, Indonesia Staff Planning

April 2022 – April 2024

- Support cruising team to meet the land clearing standard of logging or forest utilization in *PT. Sumalindo Lestari Jaya*
- Performed comprehensive spatial analysis of felling planned and actual land clearing (*PWH*) by producing maps layout and creating Web-GIS.
- Provides regular balance sheet report with calculation dan recapitulation of the amount of *PNBP* revenue (*PSDH* and *DR*) to related department.
- Reconciling PNBP payments to ensure the related department reflect the correct transaction.
- Maintain regular contact with the government relating to current obligation and payment procedure.

World Resources Institute - Jakarta, Indonesia

October 2021 – December 2021

Data Analyst and Quality Control

- Processed forest inventory data into web-map and SQL format for leaflet-based Web-GIS development.
- Analyse of carbon sequestration of each stand species based on tree allometric calculations.
- Provides GIS analysis of deforestation based on UMD (University of Maryland) and RADD (Radar for Detecting Deforestation) Tree Cover Loss data. Resulting data and maps can be viewed on *Adopsi Pohon Riau* website.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, University of Glasgow – Bandung, Indonesia

July 2021 – October 2021

Research Assistant

Conducted preliminary reconnaissance research as part of a Global Challenges Research Fund grant by interviewing
a variety of stakeholders and community members regarding birdlife trade within Indonesia.

FORRU (Forest Restoration Research Unit), Chiang Mai University - Chiang Mai, Thailand

August 2019

• Carried out post planting monitoring of forest restoration sites as part of site preparation prior to tree monitoring and participated in an environmental education program

EDUCATION

Research Intern

Institut Teknologi Bandung – Bandung, Indonesia

October 2020

Bachelor of Science, Forestry Engineering; Cumulative GPA: 3.11/4.0

ADDITIONAL

Technical: Python, R, Apache Spark, SQL, PostgreSQL, Tableau, Power BI, Microsoft Office, ArcGIS, QGIS, Agisoft,

Leaflet

Languages: Fluent in Bahasa Indonesia; Proficiency in English